<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 21:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mygluk.it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0.5</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.5/</guid>
      <description>Just after Glukloader 1.0.4, I upgraded to El Capitan (OS X 10.11) to find that Glukloader wasn&amp;rsquo;t working anymore (not synching). It seems that the behavior regarding an internal event changed in 10.11. I found an alternative and that&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s new in Glukloader 1.0.5. I also reverted a change from 1.0.4 to try and address instability issues when the receiver was plugged in on a Mac going idle. After some reading, I realized that this is something that ORSSerialPort was supposed to be handling gracefully so I decided to upgrade to the latest release (which has a few related fixes) and see where this would get me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0.4</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.4/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a bugfix release for something I hope I was the only one experiencing. I had noticed that my keyboard and mouse (and USB peripherals) on iMac would sometime stop working after it going to sleep. At first, I suspected a hardware issue but I started noticing one day that I had my Dexcom receiver plugged in before my Mac went idle. And it happened a few more times when my receiver was plugged in again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukit Goes Open-Source</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukit-goes-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukit-goes-open-source/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that I finally decided to fully open-source Glukit, Glukloader and glukameleon (a little tool used in dev) under the MIT license. The main blocker was that I needed to find a solution to keeping client ids and client secrets outside of the repository and I found something I&amp;rsquo;m happy with now.
I was hesitant to open-source Glukit for a while because much of its value resides in the centralized service that enables you to be compared to other diabetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safekeeper, Keeping Your Go Secrets Out of Git</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/safekeeper-keeping-your-secrets-out-of-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/safekeeper-keeping-your-secrets-out-of-git/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to open-source Glukit for a while but I had to find a way to keep the client ids/secrets safe and outside of git before I could do so.
Since Glukit runs on the Google App Engine, it can&amp;rsquo;t itself just read the sensitive information from environment variables. I read a post that suggested storing the secret keys in the datastore but I had quite a few and felt like this solution lacked good integration in the development flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0.2</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0.2/</guid>
      <description>I got a log file in my inbox earlier this evening. Sometimes, people write an accompanying email describing a problem but this time, I only had the log file. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to see the crash and stack trace in the logs. After a quick investigation, I found that there was a bug when the last sync had been done long enough ago that the last page synched didn&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore on the receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A1C Estimation Tweaks</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/a1c-estimation-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/a1c-estimation-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>I just realized today that my a1c color wheel wasn&amp;rsquo;t rendering properly on Safari. It&amp;rsquo;s now fixed. If you were using Safari, now the a1c display should make a lot more sense. Firefox should also be covered if you&amp;rsquo;re using a recent version.
I also made a small tweak to the a1c calculation which should result in slightly higher values. I believe this should be more accurate but I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough samples to actually know for sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Feature! Continuous A1C Estimation</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/a1c-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/a1c-estimation/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick feature annoucement post because I think most of you will understand it without much need for detailed explanation.
As of this evening, Glukit will now display an estimate of your a1c based on your most recent data available.
A few notes:
 At least 3 months of data is required for a value to be shown. From the limited samples that I have, my a1c estimates seem to be lower than reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Glukloader Version for Dexcom 505 Firmware Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/new-dexcom-firmware-new-glukloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/new-dexcom-firmware-new-glukloader/</guid>
      <description>Update: Added additional logic to seemlessly handle receiver being reset. Link updated below.
Dexcom released their new 505 firmware version earlier this week and I was happy to give it a try. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used the new version yet to confirm how better it is, but it&amp;rsquo;s looking promising. With that news also came the realization that Glukloader wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite ready for the case of receivers being reset. Thankfully, addressing it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call Out to Devs</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/call-out-to-devs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/call-out-to-devs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently the sole developer behind glukit but, like I mentionned in my intro post, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a bit drained about the 17 months of uninterrupted work on it. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to call out to diabetic developers who would be interested in pushing glukit further.
What&amp;rsquo;s Coming As of today, the main feature of glukit is the comparison with a &amp;ldquo;steady sailor&amp;rdquo;. The steady sailor at the moment is the diabetic who has the best glukit score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>♥ mmol/L</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/mmol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 21:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/mmol/</guid>
      <description>Glukit had been built with multiple glucose units in mind but, to minimize the scope of the initial testing, the front-end had been made to support only mg/dL. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that this is now no longer the case. If your Dexcom is set to mmol/L, you&amp;rsquo;ll now be able to browse your data in the unit you&amp;rsquo;re used to.
Glukloader Required Upgrade In the troubleshooting process with a friend from UK, I found a critical bug in my interpretation of the glucose values when the unit was mmol/L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0-rc20 with Time Resolution Fixes and Growl Notifications.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 22:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc20/</guid>
      <description>The last week or so has been pretty interesting (see this reddit post for some details). The first few days showed how bad assumptions can quickly become blockers and then how other assumptions can manifest themselves in more subtle ways.
Time Resolution Bugs I talked about the first blocker in the previous post but this is more about the latter. I had assumed that the Dexcom&amp;rsquo;s internal time was standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0-rc12 now available.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 21:01:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11/</guid>
      <description>Today was a big milestone for Glukit: someone else besides me used it. Or rather, someone else besides me tried to.
Given the interesting and active discussions on /r/diabetes, I had the intuition that I might find people who met my pretty strict requirements: Type 1 diabetic Dexcom G4 user with a Mac.
While this didn&amp;rsquo;t go as smoothly as I would have hoped as people were giving it a spin, I was surprised to see this much activity on my post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path to the Glukit 1.0 Preview</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 09:08:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>People who know me can attest to this (I hope): once I commit myself to doing something, I do it. Even if it makes my life miserable. Even if no one is looking and the cost of giving up is nil.
I do it because I need to create something. I do it because I know that the result might be worth it. I do it because I know that working on something brings a great satisfaction only on successful completion of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>