<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 08:30:00 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call Out to Devs</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/call-out-to-devs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 08:30:00 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/call-out-to-devs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently the sole developer behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; but, like I mentionned in my &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/introduction&#34;&gt;intro post&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a bit drained about the 17 months of uninterrupted work on it. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to call out to diabetic developers who would be interested in pushing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Coming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, the main feature of glukit is the comparison with a &amp;ldquo;steady sailor&amp;rdquo;. The steady sailor at the moment is the diabetic who has the best glukit score. And to make things more interesting, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently excluded myself from the pool of eligible users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next features I&amp;rsquo;d personally like to see in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a1c prediction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to challenge a friend to be your steady sailor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following that, I&amp;rsquo;d like to add more behavioral science nudges and potentially play with different ideas regarding the normative comparisons (aggregate comparisons with a &amp;ldquo;steady sailors&amp;rdquo; group and the average).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also some ongoing efforts to enable 3rd party uploaders to push data to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; and enable people that aren&amp;rsquo;t running on OS X to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;The Technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glukloader, the Mac OS X uploader is written in Objective-C. Glukit itself was written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; (and yes! Go is a lot of fun and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to learn) and runs on google app engine.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s front-end uses the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gumbyframework.com/&#34;&gt;gumby framework&lt;/a&gt;. Both Glukloader and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s code is hosted on github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Get in Touch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that sounds like something interesting to you, I think it could be a lot of fun. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;Glukit&lt;/a&gt; is a fully functional app but I have a nice backlog of exciting features that I think would be awesome for it. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to give this a try, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;talk to me&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>♥ mmol/L</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/mmol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 21:01:00 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/mmol/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Glukit had been built with multiple glucose units in mind but, to minimize the scope of the initial testing, the front-end had been made to support only mg/dL. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that this is now no longer the case. If your Dexcom is set to mmol/L, you&amp;rsquo;ll now be able to browse your data in the unit you&amp;rsquo;re used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Glukloader Required Upgrade&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the troubleshooting process with a friend from UK, I found a critical bug in my interpretation of the glucose values when the unit was mmol/L. If you&amp;rsquo;re a mmol user, you need to upgrade to the most recent build to get proper values: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5vrtaofgx4curih/glukloader%201.0-rc23.dmg?dl=1&#34;&gt;Glukloader 1.0-rc23&lt;/a&gt;. You should also &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt; so we can reset your data uploaded with previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build also includes a handy new feature: emailing glukit logs with a simple one-click action (in the &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo; menu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0-rc20 with Time Resolution Fixes and Growl Notifications.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 22:04:00 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc20/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The last week or so has been pretty interesting (see this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes/comments/2ei3qe/type_1_diabetic_and_software_engineer_i_thought_i/&#34;&gt;reddit post&lt;/a&gt; for some details). The first few days showed how bad assumptions can quickly become blockers and then how other assumptions can manifest themselves in more subtle ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Time Resolution Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about the first blocker in the previous post but this is more about the latter. I had assumed that the Dexcom&amp;rsquo;s internal time was standard. That is, I assumed that two receivers would have different display times but the same system time at any given point in time. That proved to be a bad assumption to make. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChickenBeard&#34;&gt;ChickenBeard&lt;/a&gt; again helped with this bug by testing my numerous builds and being patient with my varied attemps at finding a more robust solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that it looks like my new approach is now working. The bad news is that previously uploaded data is bad and locally stored archives of your data (a copy that Glukloader keeps for you and for resending data in case of disasters) is also faulty (potentially). The result is bad times (it looks like bad timezone handling). It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily dramatic but I&amp;rsquo;d like to sanitize the data at some point. More to come as I think about this and talk to a few more of you to understand the impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Growl Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Glukloader has proven to be very important to the whole interaction with Glukit, I decided to follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/edwhittle&#34;&gt;edwhittle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s suggestion and add some user feedback with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the new build with both of those: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7wjh03q9ch4sd87/glukloader%201.0-rc20.dmg?dl=1&#34;&gt;Glukloader 1.0-rc20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;talk to me&lt;/a&gt; if there&amp;rsquo;s anything on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0-rc12 now available.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 21:01:03 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a big milestone for Glukit: someone else besides me used it. Or rather, someone else besides me tried to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the interesting and active discussions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes/&#34;&gt;/r/diabetes&lt;/a&gt;, I had the intuition that I might find people who met my pretty strict requirements: Type 1 diabetic Dexcom G4 user with a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this didn&amp;rsquo;t go as smoothly as I would have hoped as people were giving it a spin, I was surprised to see this much activity on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes/comments/2ei3qe/type_1_diabetic_and_software_engineer_i_thought_i/&#34;&gt;my post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, the biggest problem was due to a bad assumption (or oversight) I made a long time ago. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t enter user events (injections, carbs) on their receiver and the receiver returns an indicator to say there&amp;rsquo;s no data. Except I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting such a value. With the logs kindly provided by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChickenBeard&#34;&gt;ChickenBeard&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to identify the bug and add tests to reproduce it. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alexandre-normand/bloodSheltie/pull/22&#34;&gt;fix it&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for my fellow redditors that were kind enough to give it a try but experienced Glukloader becoming unresponsive, this might be an update that you want to try: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dynukh1ofmvsst5/glukloader%201.0-rc12.dmg?dl=1&#34;&gt;Glukloader 1.0-rc12&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and there&amp;rsquo;s also a timezone related bug that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to isolate at the moment. Hopefully, it won&amp;rsquo;t be too long before I figure this one out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path to the Glukit 1.0 Preview</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 09:08:03 PDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;People who know me can attest to this (I hope): once I commit myself to doing something, I do it. Even if it makes my life miserable. Even if no one is looking and the cost of giving up is nil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do it because I need to create &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I do it because I know that the result might be worth it. I do it because I know that working on something brings a great satisfaction only on successful completion of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; in March 2013. We&amp;rsquo;re in August 2014, 16 months later. After an initial functional app, I had a good idea of what the minimal set of features I wanted in the 1.0 preview release. And I wanted to get that first release out. So I committed myself to making 1 commit every day until I got all of it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me a streak of &lt;a href=&#34;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5561/15004911492_19aca9abd5_c.jpg&#34;&gt;200 days of commits&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. The funny thing is that I realized only after getting hooked that my streak would only ever be visible to me because my repositories are private. But that&amp;rsquo;s not why the feature is powerful. There might be a social aspect to it but, to me, this was another behavioral science trick to help me get to a desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The Dark Side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what? I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through the making of successful creative projects like this one before. The hard part if always the life &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;. The truth is that I feel exhausted from having worked so hard without a pause for so long. That hard work and dedication got me to a significant milestone. But, now at that milestone, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find the energy to commit to the next phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Recharging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of my 2 weeks family vacation was the day I made the commit that marked the 200th day. I knew I had to wrap-up before losing focus. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that taking a break will get me to move away enough that I won&amp;rsquo;t want to get back to it. I might get drawn to something new like drawing or writing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;You&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; is also different. I did commit before I left that I would return from vacation to announce the preview release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt;. If I was successful in creating a convincing presentation of my idea for a &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;, behavioral science powered diabetes application, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll have something to tell me. Comments, suggestions, requests. I worked on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; for so long that I can&amp;rsquo;t see clearly anymore if it&amp;rsquo;s any good or if it can be effective like I imagined it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think it might have potential, I&amp;rsquo;d be excited to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;emails&lt;/a&gt; might be what fuels my next commit streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>