<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on  </title>
    <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Alexandre Normand</author>
    <rights>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported License.</rights>
    <updated>2014-08-25 21:01:03 -0700 PDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glukloader 1.0-rc12 now available.</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 21:01:03 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Ant Zucaro</author>
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/glukloader-1.0-rc11</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a big milestone for Glukit: someone else besides me used it. Or rather, someone else besides me tried to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the interesting and active discussions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes/&#34;&gt;/r/diabetes&lt;/a&gt;, I had the intuition that I might find people who met my pretty strict requirements: Type 1 diabetic Dexcom G4 user with a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this didn&amp;rsquo;t go as smoothly as I would have hoped as people were giving it a spin, I was surprised to see this much activity on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes/comments/2ei3qe/type_1_diabetic_and_software_engineer_i_thought_i/&#34;&gt;my post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, the biggest problem was due to a bad assumption (or oversight) I made a long time ago. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t enter user events (injections, carbs) on their receiver and the receiver returns an indicator to say there&amp;rsquo;s no data. Except I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting such a value. With the logs kindly provided by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChickenBeard&#34;&gt;ChickenBeard&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to identify the bug and add tests to reproduce it. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alexandre-normand/bloodSheltie/pull/22&#34;&gt;fix it&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for my fellow redditors that were kind enough to give it a try but experienced Glukloader becoming unresponsive, this might be an update that you want to try: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dynukh1ofmvsst5/glukloader%201.0-rc12.dmg?dl=1&#34;&gt;Glukloader 1.0-rc12&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and there&amp;rsquo;s also a timezone related bug that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to isolate at the moment. Hopefully, it won&amp;rsquo;t be too long before I figure this one out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path to the Glukit 1.0 Preview</title>
      <link>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 09:08:03 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Ant Zucaro</author>
      <guid>http://blog.mygluk.it/posts/introduction</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;People who know me can attest to this (I hope): once I commit myself to doing something, I do it. Even if it makes my life miserable. Even if no one is looking and the cost of giving up is nil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do it because I need to create &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I do it because I know that the result might be worth it. I do it because I know that working on something brings a great satisfaction only on successful completion of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; in March 2013. We&amp;rsquo;re in August 2014, 16 months later. After an initial functional app, I had a good idea of what the minimal set of features I wanted in the 1.0 preview release. And I wanted to get that first release out. So I committed myself to making 1 commit every day until I got all of it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me a streak of &lt;a href=&#34;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5561/15004911492_19aca9abd5_c.jpg&#34;&gt;200 days of commits&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. The funny thing is that I realized only after getting hooked that my streak would only ever be visible to me because my repositories are private. But that&amp;rsquo;s not why the feature is powerful. There might be a social aspect to it but, to me, this was another behavioral science trick to help me get to a desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The Dark Side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what? I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through the making of successful creative projects like this one before. The hard part if always the life &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;. The truth is that I feel exhausted from having worked so hard without a pause for so long. That hard work and dedication got me to a significant milestone. But, now at that milestone, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find the energy to commit to the next phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Recharging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of my 2 weeks family vacation was the day I made the commit that marked the 200th day. I knew I had to wrap-up before losing focus. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that taking a break will get me to move away enough that I won&amp;rsquo;t want to get back to it. I might get drawn to something new like drawing or writing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;You&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; is also different. I did commit before I left that I would return from vacation to announce the preview release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt;. If I was successful in creating a convincing presentation of my idea for a &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;, behavioral science powered diabetes application, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll have something to tell me. Comments, suggestions, requests. I worked on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mygluk.it/&#34;&gt;glukit&lt;/a&gt; for so long that I can&amp;rsquo;t see clearly anymore if it&amp;rsquo;s any good or if it can be effective like I imagined it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think it might have potential, I&amp;rsquo;d be excited to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexandre.normand@mygluk.it&#34;&gt;emails&lt;/a&gt; might be what fuels my next commit streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>